Charity Mbisi

🛮 +255762461585 | 💌 charitymbisi@gmail.com.com | 🧥 https://charity-eight.vercel.app | 🖸 github.com/@charity1475 | 🛅

linkedin.com/in/charity-mbisi-a6aa181a1/

Personal Profile

A Bachelor's degree student at the University of Dodoma, undertaking Software Engineering. Zealous about software engineering and with 3+ years of experience specializing in web development, algorithms, and utility plugin development. Hands-on experience in programming using Golang, Java, Javascript, and Python. Primarily, looking for Golang/Backend/Fullstack Engineering roles.

Education

University of Dodoma Dodoma, TZ

BSc in Software Engineering

Sept 2019 - Current

- School academic projects
- Part time consultant
- · Courses: Programming, Algorithms and Data structures, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Web development, Learning Skills through Case Studies, software engineering and design principles

Althash University New York, USA

Cert in Block chain Technology

April 2020 - May 2020

May 2017 - May 2019

- · Certified in Block chain Tech Foundation
- · Built and deployed a smart contract in Althash block chain

Tabora boys School Tabora, Tanzania

· Passed with Distinction

High School

· Specialised in Physics, Chemistry, and Maths with Computer Science

St James Sec School Iringa, Tanzania

Secondary School May 2013 - May 2017

• Certificate of Appreciation from District Commissioner

Work Experience

Software Engineer | Remote

Spike Labs Italy, Millano

• Associate software engineer in Leroy Merlin project(Web development project).

- coreBOS CRM API Development, Integration, Documentation, and Testing.
- coreBOS JITSU destination plugin extension.
- Mattermost plugins maintenance, extension and testing.
- Developed Airbyte ETL platform's source connector for coreBOS API configuration. Python | Docker | JSON
- Technical Skills: Golang, Python, Docker, Java, Spring Boot, JSON, Ubuntu Linux, Linux tools, Apt, Scripting, Git.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Presentation skills, Problem solving.

National Audit Office of Tanzania

Dodoma, TZ

Intern IS Auditor | Intern

July 2022 - Oct 2022

Oct 2020 - Current

- · Industrial practical training on information system audit
- Technical Skills: Data analysis, Report writing, Scripting
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Presentation skills.

Other Projects _____

Imemo software Dodoma, TZ

Alkovintage wineries Feb 2022 - Apr 2022

- · Web application and mobile app.
- Technical Skills: React, React native, Golang, MySQL.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Report writing.

Street map router Dodoma, TZ

University of Dodoma Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

- An app that used A* search algorithm to compute and show the shortest distance between two destinations in the street map routes.
- Technical Skills: C++, open street map.
- · Soft Skills: Problem solving skills, Algorithms, Logical Thinking.

JANUARY 16, 2023

t-card Dodoma, TZ

Dec 2022 - Current

University of Dodoma

- Identity cards issuing online authority.
- Technical Skills: Golang, React, Java script
- Soft Skills: Report writing, Database design

Skills

Programming Golang, Java(Spring Framework), Python, Javascript(React), C/C++, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL.

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), Kubernetes, Docker, Postgres, gRPC, CICD, Firebase, Git.

Soft Skills Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation.

Achievements

2021	Certificate, Advance Java Programming	LinkedIn
2020	Certificate, Althash University	Online
2019	Advance, ACSEE	Tanzania
2017	Secondary, CSEE	Tanzania
2012	Primary, Certificate of Primary Education Examination	Tanzania

Referees

Mr Elisha C Lembo National Audit Office of Tanzania: +255717468232

Mr Timothy Anthony Spike Labs: +255713951795

Languages _____

Swahili Native

English Professional proficiency

Latin Learning

JANUARY 16, 2023